<resources>
    <string name="app_name">How2Grow</string>

    ///Chest
    <string-array name="chest_exercises_names">
        <item>Barbell Bench Press</item>
        <item>Incline Dumbell\nBench Press</item>
        <item>Cable Chest Flyes</item>
        <item>Dips</item>
        <item>Push ups</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="chest_exercises_setup">
        <item>
                1. Lie supine (on your back) on a flat bench.\n
                2. Spread your legs, bring your feet back, and place them firmly on the ground. Either your toes or your heels should be planted on the floor.\n
                3. Arch your back.\n
                4. Dismount the barbell using a grip that is a little over shoulder-width apart.\n
                5. While holding the barbell, retract (push together) your shoulder blades and straighten your wrists.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Holding a dumbbell in each hand, sit on a bench inclined at 45 degrees and rest one dumbbell on each knee.\n
                2. As you lie back on the bench, kick the dumbbells up, one at a time, into place.\n
                3. Position the dumbbells to the sides of your chest, with your elbows bent and tucked in to your torso a little.\n
                4. Straighten your wrists.\n
                5. Spread your legs and place your feet flat on the floor.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Stand midway between two pulleys, holding one stirrup (handle) in each hand.\n
                2. Place one foot in front of the other for stability.\n
                3. Bend forwards slightly at the hips, keeping your back straight.\n
                4. Extend your arms out to your sides, keeping them slightly bent at the elbows. Your palms should be facing forward.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Mount a wide dip bar using an oblique grip (the bar should run diagonally across your palms).\n
                2. Straighten your elbows, lean forward, and flex your hips and knees slightly.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Get on your hands and knees, with your arms positioned a little wider than shoulder width.\n
                2. Extend your feet backward and straighten your body.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="chest_exercises_execution">
        <item>
                1. Inhale as you lower the barbell to your chest, keeping your elbows tucked in at a 45-degree angle.\n
                2. Exhale as you press the barbell back up to the starting position.\n
                3. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you press the dumbbells upward and inward until your arms are almost fully extended and the dumbbells nearly touch.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two and squeeze your chest.\n
                3. Inhale as you lower the dumbbells back to the starting position, or until you feel a mild stretch in your chest.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you slowly draw the stirrups together in an arcing motion, until they are positioned in front of your abdomen\n
                2. Hold for a count of two and squeeze your chest.\n
                3. Inhale as you slowly return the stirrups either to the starting position or until you feel a mild stretch in your chest.\n
                4. Repeat for the recommended number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Inhale as you bend your arms and lower your body until you feel a mild stretch in your chest or shoulders. As you descend, allow your elbows to flare out to the sides a little.\n
                2. Exhale as you push your body back up to the starting position.\n
                3. Repeat for the prescribed number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Keeping your body straight and elbows slightly tucked in, inhale as you lower your chest to the floor by bending your elbows.\n
                2. Exhale as you reverse the motion and push your body back up to the starting position.\n
                3. Repeat.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    ///Back
    <string-array name="back_exercises_names">
        <item>Conventional Deadlift</item>
        <item>Barbell Row</item>
        <item>Pulldowns</item>
        <item>Dumbbell Row</item>
        <item>Shrugs</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="back_exercises_setup">
        <item>
                1. Stand with your feet under the barbell, hip-width apart. When you look down, the barbell should run halfway over your feet.\n
                2. Bend down and grasp the barbell with a shoulder-width grip.\n
                3. Take a deep breath.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Stand over a loaded barbell, with the bar lining up with your toes.\n
                2. Bend at the hips and a little at the knees and grasp the barbell with hands a little wider than shoulder width apart. Your back should be straight and close to horizontal.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Sit on the lat pull-down machine.\n
                2. Bring the thigh pad down onto your thighs so that you are secured in place.\n
                3. Grasp the bar with a pronated (overhand) grip, with your hands a little wider than shoulder width apart (medium grip). Your arms and shoulders should be fully stretched upward.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Holding a dumbbell in your left hand, kneel on a bench with your right knee and support your body with your right arm. The dumbbell should be hanging straight down, with your left arm almost fully extended.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Stand holding a barbell using a shoulder-width pronated grip (palms facing your body).\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="back_exercises_execution">
        <item>
                1. Keeping your torso upright and your back and arms straight, stand and pull the bar up the front of your legs, driving with your legs.\n
                2. At the top of the movement, squeeze your glutes, pull your shoulders back, and exhale.\n
                3. To return the bar to the floor, push your butt backward and lower the bar down the front of your legs, keeping your back straight.\n
                4. Once the bar passes your knees, bend your knees and lower the bar to the floor.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you pull the barbell up to your waist.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two and squeeze your back muscles.\n
                3. Inhale as you lower the barbell in a controlled manner until it nearly touches the floor.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Keeping your head back and chest out, exhale as you slowly pull the bar down to the upper part of your chest.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two and squeeze your shoulder blades together.\n
                3. Inhale as you slowly return the bar to the starting position, with your arms and shoulders fully stretched.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you pull the dumbbell up to the side of your waist.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two.\n
                3. Inhale as you lower the dumbbell to the starting position.\n
                4. Repeat for the desired number of reps.\n
                5. Repeat with your right arm.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you elevate your shoulders as high as possible.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two and squeeze your trapezius.\n
                3. Inhale as you lower the barbell back to the starting position.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    ///Shoulders
    <string-array name="shoulders_exercises_names">
        <item>Barbell Overhead\nPress</item>
        <item>Dumbbell Lateral\nRaises</item>
        <item>Dumbbell Reverse\nFlyes</item>
        <item>Facepulls</item>
        <item>Dumbbell Front\nRaises</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="shoulders_exercises_setup">
        <item>
                1. Stand with your feet shoulder-width apart, holding a barbell with a pronated (overhand) grip at upper-chest height.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Stand holding a dumbbell in each hand, with the dumbbells hanging down by your sides.\n
                2. Bend forward a little at the hips.\n
                3. Eternally rotate your shoulders so that your thumbs point out diagonally.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Holding a pair of dumbbells, sit on the end of a bench.\n
                2. Lean forward until your torso is as close to horizontal as possible and allow your arms to hang down by your feet. Your palms should be facing each other (neutral grip).\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Stand in front of a pulley set at approximately head height.\n
                2. Grasp one end of the rope attachment in each hand using a supinated (underhand) grip.\n
                3. Step backward so that the rope is taut and your arms are stretched out in front of you.\n
                4. Assume a staggered stance (place one foot in front of the other) and lean backward to help you balance.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Stand grasping a barbell with an overhand grip, with your hands shoulder-width apart and your elbows extended.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="shoulders_exercises_execution">
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you push the barbell straight upward.\n
                2. At the top of the movement, shrug your shoulders to raise the barbell even higher.\n
                3. Inhale as you reverse the motions and lower the barbell to the starting position in a controlled manner.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Keeping your elbows slightly bent, exhale as you raise both upper arms out to the sides until your elbows are level with your shoulders.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two.\n
                3. Inhale as you lower the dumbbells to the starting position.\n
                4. Repeat for the recommended number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Keeping your arms slightly bent and your elbows perpendicular to your torso, exhale as you raise your arms out to the sides until your elbows are shoulder height.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two.\n
                3. Inhale as you lower your arms to the starting position in a controlled manner.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you pull the rope toward your forehead.\n
                2. As the rope nears your face, externally rotate your shoulders so that you end up making a double biceps pose.\n
                3. Hold for a count of two.\n
                4. Inhale as you reverse the motion and return the rope to the starting position in a controlled manner.\n
                5. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Keeping your arms straight and your back neutral, exhale as you lift the barbell forward and upward until your arms are a little above horizontal.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two.\n
                3. Inhale as you lower the barbell back to the starting position.\n
                4. Repeat for the desired number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    ///Quads
    <string-array name="quads_exercises_names">
        <item>Squat</item>
        <item>Bulgarian Split\nSquat</item>
        <item>Leg Extensions</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="quads_exercises_setup">
        <item>
                1. Load a barbell on a rack at upper-chest height.\n
                2. Step under the barbell so that it rests on the back of your shoulders, and grasp the bar at each side.\n
                3. Dismount the barbell and step backward carefully. Your feet should be shoulder-width apart and pointing slightly outwards.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Holding a pair of dumbbells by your sides, stand with your back facing the side of a bench. There should be three or four feet of space between you and the bench.\n
                2. Extend one leg backward and place the top of your foot on the bench so that your body is being supported by only one leg.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Choose your weight and sit on the leg extension machine.\n
                2. Make the necessary adjustments so that the backs of your thighs are fully supported by the seat and your back is fully supported by the back rest.\n
                3. Hook your feet under the foot pads of the lever with the pads resting just above your ankles.\n
                4. Grasp the side handles for support.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="quads_exercises_execution">
        <item>
                1. Inhale as you squat down by simultaneously pushing your butt backward and bending your knees forward. Keep your torso upright, and descend at least until your knees are bent at a 90-degree angle.\n
                2. Exhale as you push your body back up to the starting position, driving through your heels and keeping your torso upright.\n
                3. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Keeping your torso upright, inhale as you squat down with your supporting leg until the knee of your back leg nearly touches the floor.\n
                2. Exhale as you push yourself back up to the starting position, driving through your heel.\n
                3. Repeat for the prescribed number of repetitions.\n
                4. Repeat the exercise with your opposite leg.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you lift the lever forwards and upwards by straightening your legs until they are fully extended.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two.\n
                3. Inhale as you return the lever to the starting position by bending your knees.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    ///Hams
    <string-array name="hams_exercises_names">
        <item>Stiff Legged\nDeadlift</item>
        <item>Leg Curls</item>
        <item>Nordic Curls</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="hams_exercises_setup">
        <item>
                1. Grasp a barbell using a shoulder-width pronated (overhand) grip or a mixed grip.\n
                2. Keeping your back straight, head up, and hips low, lift the barbell into a standing position.\n
                3. Flex your knees a little.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Sit in the leg curl machine.\n
                2. Place the backs of your lower legs on top of the padded lever.\n
                3. Lower the thigh support so that it rests just above your knees (missing from illustration; see video).\n
                4. Hold the handles for support.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Get on your knees and anchor the back of your heels under a bench or a barbell. Ideally, your feet should be fully dorsally flexed (i.e. your toes should be pointing up to your shins).\n
                2. Flex your hips a little.\n
                3. Cross your arms over your chest (or you can keep them by your sides).\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="hams_exercises_execution">
        <item>
                1. Keeping your back straight and your knees slightly flexed (stiff), inhale as you push your hips backward and slowly lower the barbell down the front of your legs. Descend until you feel a mild stretch in your hamstrings.\n
                2. Exhale as you pull the barbell back up to the starting position by pushing your hips forward.\n
                3. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you flex your knees and curl the lever all the way to the back of your thighs.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two and squeeze your hamstrings.\n
                3. Inhale as you return the lever to the starting position.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Inhale as you allow your body to slowly fall forward, controlling the descent as much as you can with your hamstrings.\n
                2. At the bottom of the movement, catch your body with your arms and lower your torso to the floor as if performing a knee push-up.\n
                3. Exhale as you push your torso back up and off the floor just enough until your hamstrings can take over and pull your body back up to a vertical position.\n
                4. Repeat for the prescribed number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    ///Biceps
    <string-array name="biceps_exercises_names">
        <item>Dumbbell Curls</item>
        <item>Dumbbell Incline\nCurls</item>
        <item>Preacher Curls</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="biceps_exercises_setup">
        <item>
                1. Stand holding a dumbbell in each hand, allowing the dumbbells to hang by your sides, with your palms facing in (neutral grip).\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Holding a pair of dumbbells using a hammer (neutral) grip (palms in), sit on an inclined bench.\n
                2. Rest your back on the inclined bench and allow your arms to hang down by the sides of your body.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Holding a dumbbell in each hand, sit on the preacher bench.\n
                2. With your elbows flexed, place the backs of your upper arms flat on the arm rest.\n
                3. Supinate your wrists (i.e. rotate them so that your palms face you).\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="biceps_exercises_execution">
        <item>
                1. Keeping your back neutral and torso upright, exhale as you curl the dumbbells up to your shoulders. As the dumbbells rise, slightly rotate your forearms so that your palms face your shoulders by the top of the curl.\n
                2. Once your elbows are fully flexed, allow your elbow to slightly move forward until your forearms are vertical.\n
                3. Hold for a count of two. Squeeze your biceps.\n
                4. Inhale as you slowly lower the dumbbells back to the starting position, rotating your palms back to face inwards.\n
                5. Repeat for the desired number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Keeping a neutral grip and the rest of your body stationary, exhale as you lift the dumbbells up to the sides of your chest by flexing your elbows.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two and squeeze your biceps.\n
                3. Inhale as you slowly reverse the motion to return the dumbbells to the starting position.\n
                4. Repeat for the desired number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Keeping your wrists supinated, inhale as you lower the dumbbells until your elbows are almost fully extended.\n
                2. Exhale as you curl the dumbbells back up toward your shoulders.\n
                3. At the top of the movement, hold for a count of two and squeeze your biceps brachii.\n
                4. Repeat for the prescribed number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    ///Triceps
    <string-array name="triceps_exercises_names">
        <item>Barbell Skullcrushers</item>
        <item>Dumbbell Overhead\nExtensions</item>
        <item>Diamond Pushups</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="triceps_exercises_setup">
        <item>
                1. Lie on your back (supine) on a flat bench.\n
                2. Dismount the barbell using a pronated (overhand), shoulder-width grip and hold the barbell over your forehead so that your arms are slightly slanted backwards.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Stand holding a dumbbell in one hand using a neutral grip.\n
                2. Lift the dumbbell up over your head and slightly back, with your elbow bent and pointed up towards the ceiling.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Get on your hands and knees, with your hands close together and your thumbs and index fingers forming a diamond shape.\n
                2. Extend your feet backward and straighten your body so that your bodyweight is being supported by your hands and forefeet.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="triceps_exercises_execution">
        <item>
                1. Keeping your upper arms still, inhale as you lower the barbell toward your forehead in a smooth, semicircular motion by flexing your elbows.\n
                2. Exhale as you reverse the movement and push the barbell back up to the starting position by extending your elbows.\n
                3. Repeat for the prescribed number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale while pushing the dumbbell upwards until your arm is extended. Keep your elbow close to your head and the dumbbell behind your head.\n
                2. Inhale as you lower the dumbbell back to the starting position.\n
                3. Repeat for the prescribed number of repetitions.\n
                4. Repeat with the opposite arm.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Keeping your elbows tucked in to your body and your body straight and rigid, inhale as you lower your chest to the floor.\n
                2. Exhale as you extend your elbows and push your body back up to the starting position.\n
                3. Repeat for the prescribed number of repetitions.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    ///ABS
    <string-array name="abs_exercises_names">
        <item>Crunches</item>
        <item>Hanging Leg Raises</item>
        <item>Plank</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="abs_exercises_setup">
        <item>
                1. Lie supine (on your back) with your legs bent and your feet flat on the ground.\n
                2. Place your hands lightly either behind or by the sides of your head, keeping your elbows out.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Hang from a high bar with your hands shoulder-with apart, your arms fully extended, and your legs straight.\n
                2. Straighten your lower back by tilting your pelvis backward.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Get down on all fours on a mat.\n
                2. Gently lower your upper body onto your elbows, extend your feet backward, and straighten your body. Your feet should be close together, your elbows should be directly under your shoulders, and your rigid body should be being supported by your forearms and toes.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="abs_exercises_execution">
        <item>
                1. Keeping your lower back flat on the floor, raise your head and shoulders a few inches off the ground by flexing your abdomen. Exhale as you do so.\n
                2. Hold the contracted position for a count of two.\n
                3. Inhale as you lower your head and shoulders to the starting position.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Exhale as you slowly raise your knees as high as possible by flexing your hips and your abdomen.\n
                2. Hold for a count of two.\n
                3. Inhale as you slowly lower your legs to the starting position.\n
                4. Repeat.\n
        </item>
        <item>
                1. Hold this position for the desired period of time, breathing normally.\n
                2. Slowly return to the starting position.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    ///Nutrition basics
    <string-array name="nutrition_basics">
        <item>1. Calorie Intake: You need to consume enough calories to support your training and muscle growth. This requires you to consume a caloric surplus, which means consuming more calories than you burn. Unless you want to reduce body fat then your calories intake should be lower that your body really needs so it will be forced to take energy from stored fat. Surplus or deficit depending on your goals of around 500 calories is recommended for starters</item>
        <item>2. Macronutrient Balance: Adequate protein, carbohydrate, and fat intake is important for muscle growth and recovery. Protein intake should be high (around 1g per pound of bodyweight) to support muscle protein synthesis, while carbohydrates are essential for energy during workouts (but they are not necessary so they just make up the rest of your diet after protein and fats), and fat is necessary for hormone production and overall health (you should consume no less than 0.3g of healthy fats per pound of body weight).</item>
        <item>3. Meal Timing: Consuming protein and carbohydrates after your workout can help to promote muscle recovery and growth. Additionally, consuming meals and snacks throughout the day can help to provide the necessary nutrients to fuel your workouts and recovery.</item>
        <item>4. Hydration: Adequate hydration is crucial for optimal performance and recovery. Dehydration can negatively impact strength and energy levels, so it is important to drink enough water throughout the day.</item>
        <item>5. Micronutrients: Vitamins and minerals are important for overall health and performance. Eating a variety of fruits, vegetables, whole grains, and lean protein sources can help to ensure adequate micronutrient intake.</item>
        <item>6. Individualization: Everyone has different nutritional needs and preferences. Your nutrition plan should be tailored to your individual needs, goals, and preferences.</item>
        <item>7. Consistency: Consistent healthy eating habits are key to achieving and maintaining optimal health and performance. Consistently eating a balanced diet that supports your training goals is important for long-term success.</item>
    </string-array>

    ///Exercise basics
    <string-array name="exercise_basics">
        <item>1. Overload: To improve strength, you must challenge your muscles with heavier resistance than they are accustomed to. This principle states that in order to make progress, the resistance or load you lift must be increased over time.</item>

        <item>2. Specificity: This principle states that you must train the muscle groups and movements that you want to improve. For example, if you want to improve your squat, you must perform squatting exercises.</item>

        <item>3. Progression: This principle is related to overload and states that you must gradually increase the resistance or intensity of your training over time. This helps to prevent plateau and ensures continued progress.</item>

        <item>4. Intensity: If you are willing to make progress your workouts should be intense. You need to put actual effort into every session, because just showing up is not enough to make real progress long-term.</item>

        <item>5. Recovery: Rest and recovery are important aspects of strength training. Giving your muscles time to recover between workouts allows them to repair and rebuild, leading to strength gains.</item>

        <item>6. Individualization: Everyone has different strengths, weaknesses, and goals. Your strength training program should be tailored to your individual needs and abilities.</item>

        <item>7. Consistency: Consistency is key to making progress in strength training. You need to be consistent with your training and follow your program regularly in order to see results.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>